Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we have another episode in our series all about giving presentations
我是Catherine，这是我们关于做演示系列的另一集。
in English.
用英语做演示。
So this is show number eight for us.
所以这是我们的第八集节目。
That's right.
没错。
We're getting towards the end of the series.
我们快接近这个系列的尾声了。
On this occasion, on presentation series number eight, we're going to continue with Mr. Ford
这次，在演示系列第八集中，我们将继续跟随Ford先生。
and try to handle a couple of problems that keep coming up.
并尝试处理一些反复出现的问题。
All right.
好的。
So take a listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to discuss it.
那么先来听听我们的对话，稍后我们会回来讨论。
So as I mentioned previously, the campaign advertisement will focus on those key elements
正如我之前提到的，这次广告宣传活动将聚焦于那些关键要素。
that every consumer looks for in a quality laptop.
每个消费者在选购优质笔记本电脑时都会看重的要素。
Affordability, quality, speed, and reliability.
价格实惠、质量好、速度快、可靠性高。
We've pulled out all the stops to produce a product that really rivals all our competitors.
我们竭尽全力生产出一款真正能与所有竞争对手抗衡的产品。
Actually, just to illustrate my point, let me give you an anecdote here.
实际上，为了说明我的观点，让我给你们讲个小故事。
I remember last year I was playing golf with one of our key suppliers.
我记得去年我和我们的一位主要供应商打高尔夫。
It was a lovely summer afternoon.
那是一个美好的夏日午后。
Anyway, I invited our supplier for a game of golf and wanted to get his input on the
总之，我邀请供应商打了一场高尔夫，想听听他对新款X420的看法。
new X420.
新款X420。
Actually, I often get together with him for a good game of golf.
实际上，我经常和他一起打高尔夫。
It really is a wonderful way to relax.
这真是一种绝佳的放松方式。
To be honest, I'm not that great at golf, but I've improved in the last few years.
说实话，我高尔夫打得不太好，但过去几年进步了不少。
But the key to golf is practice, practice, practice.
但高尔夫的关键就是练习、练习、再练习。
Sorry, I've lost my thread.
抱歉，我思路断了。
What was I talking about again?
我刚才说到哪儿了？
I think you were discussing the campaign advertisement, Michael.
我想你刚才在讨论广告宣传活动，Michael。
Yes, excuse me.
是的，抱歉。
I'm afraid I got sidetracked there.
我恐怕刚才跑题了。
Yes, anyway, the campaign.
好的，总之，这个宣传活动。
Well, let me see.
嗯，让我想想。
Is the projector working yet, Jonathan?
投影仪修好了吗，Jonathan？
No, sorry.
没有，抱歉。
IT is still fixing it.
IT部门还在修。
Okay.
好的。
Well, all the information on the campaign is on the PowerPoint.
嗯，所有关于宣传活动的信息都在PowerPoint里。
I haven't actually got my notes with me.
我实际上没带笔记。
Let me see.
让我想想。
Mr. Ford, could you at least tell us the schedule for the campaign?
Ford先生，您至少能告诉我们宣传活动的日程安排吗？
When are the first advertisements scheduled for?
第一批广告计划什么时候投放？
That's a good question.
问得好。
Unfortunately, I don't have that information on me.
不幸的是，我手头没有那个信息。
I'll have to get back to you on that point.
我得回头再答复你这个问题。
Okay, Michael.
好的，Michael。
The projector is fixed.
投影仪修好了。
I think we're ready.
我想我们准备好了。
Thank goodness.
谢天谢地。
Okay, everyone.
好的，各位。
Sorry for the delay.
抱歉耽误了时间。
So without further ado, the new X420 marketing campaign.
那么闲话少说，新款X420的营销宣传活动。
Enjoy!
请欣赏！
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
哦，非常抱歉。
This is not the advert.
这不是广告。
This is my golfing holiday in Barbados.
这是我在巴巴多斯的高尔夫度假照片。
I think I must have brought the wrong file.
我想我一定是拿错文件了。
Can we take five?
我们能休息五分钟吗？
Come on, Mr. Ford.
拜托了，Ford先生。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
And Mr. Ford faced a very embarrassing moment here.
Ford先生在这里遇到了一个非常尴尬的时刻。
But he also used a lot of interesting vocab.
但他也用了很多有趣的词汇。
Why don't we take a look at that now on Language Takeaway.
我们现在就在“语言小贴士”环节来看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So at the beginning of today's dialogue, we heard a word that's very interesting.
在今天对话的开头，我们听到了一个非常有趣的词。
An anecdote.
轶事。
What is an anecdote, Marco?
什么是轶事，Marco？
Right.
对。
He started telling a story and that's basically an anecdote, a life experience or a story,
他开始讲一个故事，那基本上就是轶事，一段人生经历或一个故事。
something that happened to you and you want to share with people.
发生在你身上并想与人分享的事情。
Right.
对。
So an anecdote is a story.
所以轶事就是一个故事。
So he was talking about golfing with a client and this is why.
他当时在讲和客户打高尔夫的事，这就是原因。
And so this is called an anecdote.
所以这被称为轶事。
He was telling a story about it.
他在讲一个关于这件事的故事。
After that, though, we realized that he is a little bit distracted.
不过在那之后，我们意识到他有点分心。
He says, I'm afraid I got sidetracked there.
他说：“我恐怕刚才跑题了。”
That's right.
没错。
So he's obviously talking about the computer and the marketing campaign.
所以他显然在谈论电脑和营销宣传活动。
And then he starts talking about golf and how great it is.
然后他开始谈论高尔夫以及它有多棒。
So he says, I got sidetracked.
所以他说：“我跑题了。”
And that means that you got distracted or you started talking about something that's
这意味着你分心了，或者开始谈论与主题无关的事情。
not related to the topic.
与话题无关。
So I really like to eat hamburgers and I like hamburgers with cheese, actually.
所以我真的很喜欢吃汉堡，而且实际上我喜欢加奶酪的汉堡。
But wait, sorry, just got a little sidetracked there.
但是等等，抱歉，我刚才有点走神了。
I think we should focus on English right now.
我觉得我们现在应该专注于英语。
That's right.
没错。
So it happens sometimes maybe you're even, maybe you're even talking to someone and something
有时候会发生这种情况，也许你正在，也许你正在和别人说话，而某件事
is happening behind that person.
正在那个人身后发生。
You get sidetracked and you're not really paying attention.
你走神了，并没有真正在听。
That's right.
没错。
And then after that, we realized that there's still a problem with the projector.
然后在那之后，我们意识到投影仪还有问题。
And Mr. Ford asks if it's working yet.
福特先生问它修好了没有。
Jonathan, his assistant says, no, sorry, IT are still fixing it.
他的助理乔纳森说，不，抱歉，IT部门还在修。
All right.
好的。
So this acronym IT, I think many of you have heard it and it means for information technology.
所以这个缩写IT，我想很多人都听过，它代表信息技术。
Okay.
好的。
Information technology that has to do with computers.
信息技术，与计算机相关。
And so when we have a technical problem or a computer problem, we usually call IT.
所以当我们遇到技术问题或电脑问题时，我们通常会找IT部门。
That's right.
没错。
So your company probably has an IT department, or if you have, as Catherine said, a problem
所以你的公司可能有一个IT部门，或者如果你像凯瑟琳说的那样，电脑出了问题，
with your computer, you just call IT to get them to fix it for you.
你就打电话给IT部门让他们帮你修好。
Exactly.
没错。
Another computer related word comes up later when Mr. Ford says that all of the information
另一个跟电脑相关的词在后面会出现，当福特先生说所有关于竞选的信息都在 PowerPoint 上时。
about the campaign is on the PowerPoint.
关于竞选的信息都在 PowerPoint 上。
That's right.
对。
So PowerPoint, this is a computer program that is very well known for giving presentations.
所以 PowerPoint，这是一个非常著名的用于做演示的电脑程序。
So you probably use this if you ever have to give a presentation.
所以如果你需要做演示，你很可能用过它。
That's right.
对。
PowerPoint is a part of the Microsoft Office suite.
PowerPoint 是微软 Office 套件的一部分。
So you know the program Word or the program Excel.
所以你知道 Word 程序或 Excel 程序。
So PowerPoint helps you use your computer to give a presentation.
所以 PowerPoint 帮助你用电脑做演示。
So you often hear us just talk about PowerPoint.
所以你经常听到我们只提 PowerPoint。
Can you help me with this PowerPoint in English?
你能帮我用英语做这个 PowerPoint 吗？
That's right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So that's all the words we have for you on Language Takeaway.
这就是我们在“语言小贴士”部分为你准备的所有单词。
Why don't we listen to Mr. Ford again, and we'll be back soon with Fluency Builder.
我们不如再听一遍福特先生的话，稍后我们会回来继续“流利度训练”。
So as I mentioned previously, the campaign advertisement will focus on those key elements
正如我之前提到的，竞选广告将聚焦于每个消费者在优质笔记本电脑中寻找的那些关键要素。
that every consumer looks for in a quality laptop.
每个消费者在优质笔记本电脑中寻找的那些关键要素。
Affordability, quality, speed, and reliability.
价格实惠、质量好、速度快、可靠性高。
We have pulled out all the stops to produce a product that really rivals all our competitors.
我们竭尽全力生产出一款真正能与所有竞争对手匹敌的产品。
Actually, just to illustrate my point, let me give you an anecdote here.
其实，为了说明我的观点，我给你们讲个趣事吧。
I remember last year I was playing golf with one of our key suppliers.
我记得去年我和我们一个主要供应商一起打高尔夫。
It was a lovely summer afternoon.
那是一个美好的夏日午后。
Anyway, I invited our supplier for a game of golf and wanted to get his input on the
总之，我邀请供应商打了一场高尔夫，想听听他对
new X420.
新款X420的看法。
Actually, I often get together with him for a good game of golf.
其实，我经常和他一起打高尔夫。
It really is a wonderful way to relax.
这真是个放松的好方式。
To be honest, I'm not that great at golf, but I've improved in the last few years.
说实话，我高尔夫打得不太好，但过去几年进步了不少。
But the key to golf is practice, practice, practice.
但高尔夫的关键就是练习、练习、再练习。
Sorry, I've lost my thread.
抱歉，我跑题了。
What was I talking about again?
我刚才说到哪儿了？
I think you were discussing the campaign advertisement, Michael.
我想你刚才在讨论广告宣传活动，迈克尔。
Yes, excuse me.
是的，不好意思。
I'm afraid I got sidetracked there.
我恐怕刚才跑题了。
Yes, anyway, the campaign.
对，总之，那个宣传活动。
Well, let me see.
嗯，让我想想。
Is the projector working yet, Jonathan?
投影仪修好了吗，乔纳森？
No, sorry.
还没，抱歉。
IT is still fixing it.
IT部门还在修。
Okay.
好的。
Well, all the information on the campaign is on the PowerPoint.
嗯，这次活动的所有信息都在PPT里了。
I haven't actually got my notes with me.
我其实没带我的笔记。
Let me see.
让我看看。
Mr. Ford, could you at least tell us the schedule for the campaign?
福特先生，您至少能告诉我们活动的日程安排吗？
When are the first advertisements scheduled for?
第一批广告计划在什么时候投放？
That's a good question.
这个问题问得好。
Unfortunately, I don't have that information on me.
可惜，我手头没有这个信息。
I'll have to get back to you on that point.
我得回头再答复你这一点。
Okay, Michael.
好的，迈克尔。
The projector is fixed.
投影仪修好了。
I think we're ready.
我想我们准备好了。
Thank goodness.
谢天谢地。
Okay, everyone.
好了，各位。
Sorry for the delay.
抱歉让大家久等了。
So without further ado, the new X420 marketing campaign.
那么，闲话少说，新的X420营销活动。
Enjoy!
请欣赏！
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
哦，非常抱歉。
This is not the advert.
这不是广告。
This is my golfing holiday in Barbados.
这是我在巴巴多斯的高尔夫度假视频。
I think I must have brought the wrong file.
我想我一定是拿错文件了。
Can we take five?
我们能休息五分钟吗？
Come on, Mr. Ford.
拜托了，福特先生。
All right.
好吧。
So we've picked out a lot of great phrases for you today.
今天我们为你挑选了很多好用的短语。
Let's start with the first one on Fluency Builder.
我们先从流利度提升表上的第一个开始。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升表。
At the very beginning, Mr. Ford says we have pulled out all the stops to make a really
一开始，福特先生说我们竭尽全力打造了一款非常
great product.
出色的产品。
That's right.
没错。
So the phrase used here, to pull out all the stops, what does that mean?
那么这里用的短语“to pull out all the stops”是什么意思？
Well, you don't have to think about what it actually means.
嗯，你不用去想它的字面意思。
We use this when we're trying to say that we've done our best.
当我们想说我们已经尽了最大努力时，就会用这个短语。
We have really gone as far as we can, 100%.
我们真的已经全力以赴，100%投入了。
We're giving everything we can to make this thing the best that it can be.
我们倾尽所有，让这个东西做到最好。
Okay.
好的。
So you've put a lot of effort and resources into making something great.
所以你投入了大量精力和资源来打造一个很棒的东西。
You didn't hold back.
你没有保留。
You didn't save any money.
你没有省钱。
You just went for it.
你直接放手去做了。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
Now when we were talking about Mr. Ford being distracted and he started talking about golf,
当我们谈到福特先生走神，开始聊高尔夫时，
he said, oh, I'm sorry, I've lost my thread.
他说，哦，对不起，我思路断了。
What was I talking about again?
我刚才在说什么来着？
All right.
好的。
So this is interesting because the word thread can mean something that you, it's like a string
这很有意思，因为“thread”这个词可以指你用来缝衣服的线，
that you use to sew clothes with.
就像一根线。
But in this particular case, we're talking about a thread of conversation.
但在这个特定情况下，我们说的是谈话的线索。
And so that's basically the topic that he's talking about.
所以基本上就是他正在谈论的话题。
Okay.
好的。
So when he said, I lost my thread, he makes reference to the thread of conversation of
所以当他说“我思路断了”时，他指的是他正在谈论的谈话线索
what he was talking about.
断了。
Right.
对。
So he's talking about golf, but he lost his thread.
所以他正在聊高尔夫，但思路断了。
So then he doesn't remember what he was talking about.
然后他就不记得自己刚才在说什么了。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And Mr. Ford actually faced a couple of questions from the audience members.
福特先生实际上还面对了观众提出的几个问题。
One of them asked about the schedule for the campaign and he said, you know what, I really
其中一个人问到了活动的日程安排，他说，你知道吗，我真的
don't have that information.
没有那个信息。
I will have to get back to you on that point.
我得回头再回答你这个问题。
Well, this is a really great way to answer a question you don't actually know how to
嗯，这真的是回答你不知道怎么回答的问题的一个好方法。
answer.
回答。
In this case, Mr. Ford doesn't have the answer to this, this audience member's question,
在这种情况下，福特先生没有这个观众问题的答案，
like you said, Marco.
就像你说的，马可。
He just says, I will have to get back to you on that.
他只是说，我得回头再回答你这个问题。
I will have to let you know later.
我以后会告诉你。
So it's a much better, so it's much better to say, I will get back to you instead of
所以这样说更好，说“我会回头再告诉你”比
saying, I don't know.
说“我不知道”好得多。
For example, if your boss asks you, I don't know, how were sales last year compared to
比如，如果你的老板问你，我不知道，去年的销售额和今年相比
this year?
怎么样？
And if you don't know, it's really not recommendable to say, I don't know.
如果你不知道，真的不建议说“我不知道”。
You don't want to say, I don't know.
你不想说“我不知道”。
It makes you sound like you don't know anything.
那会让你听起来好像什么都不知道。
So in this case, you say, listen, I really have to get back to you about that.
所以在这种情况下，你说，听着，我真的得回头再回答你这个问题。
I want to check some numbers.
我想查一下一些数字。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay, so moving on to our next phrase.
好的，那我们继续下一个短语。
When finally he was going to present the ad campaign, he said, so without further ado,
当他最后要展示广告活动时，他说，那么，闲话少说，
the new 420 marketing campaign.
新的420营销活动。
This phrase, without further ado, is something that we commonly hear in speeches or more
这个短语“without further ado”我们在演讲或更正式的场合经常听到，
formal occasions, but it's something that we say when we want to introduce something.
但当我们想介绍某样东西时，也会用到它。
We say, we're not going to talk about it anymore.
我们说，我们不再多说了。
Let's just do it.
直接开始吧。
Let's just show you.
直接展示给你看。
So the word ado, is this, this is I think like classic English.
所以“ado”这个词，我觉得这算是经典英语。
It's not really common to hear it anymore.
现在不太常听到了。
No, there is actually a very famous play by Shakespeare called Much Ado About Nothing.
不，实际上莎士比亚有一部非常著名的戏剧叫《无事生非》。
And that means, you know, that there's a lot of talking and a lot of problems and a lot
那意思是，你知道，关于这一件事有很多谈论、很多问题和很多
of drama about this one thing.
戏剧性。
And so basically when we say the phrase without further ado, we're saying, you know, without
所以基本上当我们说“without further ado”这个短语时，我们是在说，你知道，不再
further talking, talking about this anymore.
多说了，不再谈论这个了。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a nice way to say, okay, finally we're going to do this, or finally we're going to
所以这是一种很好的说法，表示，好了，我们终于要做这个了，或者我们终于要
see this.
看到这个了。
And obviously the video was not the campaign.
显然，视频并不是那个活动。
It was his golfing holiday in Barbados.
而是他在巴巴多斯的高尔夫假期。
So he asked someone if he could take five.
所以他问别人他能不能休息五分钟。
All right.
好的。
This phrase to take five is very, very common in English.
这个短语“to take five”在英语中非常非常常见。
And it's just another way to say, can we take a five minute break?
它只是另一种说法，表示“我们能休息五分钟吗？”
So maybe you can ask your teacher, excuse me, can we, can we take five or, or something
所以也许你可以问你的老师，不好意思，我们能不能休息五分钟或类似的时间？
like that?
类似这样的？
Yeah.
是的。
Or, hey guys, I'm, I'm, I need a glass of water.
或者，嘿，各位，我、我需要一杯水。
Let's take five.
我们休息五分钟吧。
Right.
对。
So that means let's have a short break.
所以那意思是让我们短暂休息一下。
Let's take a five minute break, but it doesn't always necessarily have to be five minutes.
让我们休息五分钟，但也不一定非得是五分钟。
Now it can be seven minutes or 10 minutes, but take five means a short break.
可以是七分钟或十分钟，但“take five”指的是短暂休息。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So you don't say, can we take 10 or can we take seven?
所以你别说“我们能休息十分钟”或“我们能休息七分钟”。
Now usually just say take five, take five.
通常就说“take five”，“take five”。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
行。
So a lot of phrases there, a lot of great stuff.
所以这里有很多短语，很多好东西。
Let's review it one last time.
让我们最后复习一遍。
So as I mentioned previously, the campaign advertisement will focus on those key elements
所以正如我之前提到的，广告宣传活动将聚焦于那些关键要素，
that every consumer looks for in a quality laptop, affordability, quality, speed, and
每个消费者在优质笔记本电脑中寻找的：价格实惠、质量、速度和
reliability.
可靠性。
We have pulled out all the stops to produce a product that really rivals all our competitors.
我们竭尽全力生产出一款真正能与所有竞争对手抗衡的产品。
Actually, just to illustrate my point, let me give you an anecdote here.
实际上，为了说明我的观点，让我给你讲个轶事。
I remember last year I was playing golf with one of our key suppliers.
我记得去年我和我们一个主要供应商打高尔夫球。
It was a lovely summer afternoon.
那是一个美好的夏日午后。
Anyway, I invited our supplier for a game of golf and wanted to get his input on the
总之，我邀请供应商打了一场高尔夫球，想听听他对
new X420.
新款X420的看法。
Actually, I often get together with him for a good game of golf.
实际上，我经常和他一起打一场好高尔夫球。
It really is a wonderful way to relax.
这真是一种放松的好方式。
To be honest, I'm not that great at golf, but I've improved in the last few years.
说实话，我高尔夫打得不太好，但过去几年进步了。
But the key to golf is practice, practice, practice.
但高尔夫的关键是练习、练习、再练习。
I'm sorry, I've lost my thread.
抱歉，我思路断了。
What was I talking about again?
我刚才在说什么来着？
I think you were discussing the campaign advertisement, Michael.
我想你刚才在讨论广告宣传活动，迈克尔。
Yes, excuse me.
是的，不好意思。
I'm afraid I got sidetracked there.
我恐怕刚才跑题了。
Yes.
是的。
Anyway, the campaign.
总之，宣传活动。
Well, let me see.
嗯，让我想想。
Is the projector working yet, Jonathan?
投影仪修好了吗，乔纳森？
No, sorry.
没有，抱歉。
IT is still fixing it.
IT部门还在修。
Okay.
好的。
Well, all the information on the campaign is on the PowerPoint.
嗯，所有关于宣传活动的信息都在PPT里。
I haven't actually got my notes with me.
我实际上没带笔记。
Let me see.
让我想想。
Mr. Ford, could you at least tell us the schedule for the campaign?
福特先生，您至少能告诉我们宣传活动的日程吗？
When are the first advertisements scheduled for?
第一批广告计划什么时候投放？
That's a good question.
问得好。
Unfortunately, I don't have that information on me.
不幸的是，我手头没有那个信息。
I'll have to get back to you on that point.
我得回头再告诉你那个问题。
Okay, Michael.
好的，迈克尔。
The projector is fixed.
投影仪修好了。
I think we're ready.
我想我们准备好了。
Thank goodness.
谢天谢地。
Okay, everyone.
好了，各位。
Sorry for the delay.
抱歉耽误了。
So without further ado, the new X420 marketing campaign.
所以闲话少说，新款X420营销宣传活动。
Enjoy.
请欣赏。
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
哦，非常抱歉。
This is not the advert.
这不是广告。
This is my golfing holiday in Barbados.
这是我在巴巴多斯的高尔夫假期照片。
I think I must have brought the wrong file.
我想我一定是拿错文件了。
Can we take five?
我们能休息五分钟吗？
Come on, Mr. Ford.
拜托了，福特先生。
Okay, so we're coming towards the end of our presentation series.
好的，我们即将结束我们的演示系列。
So be sure to listen to us next week when we're talking about presentation series part
所以请务必在下周收听我们，届时我们将讨论演示系列第九
nine.
部分。
And as you may know, it ends with part 10.
正如你可能知道的，它会在第十部分结束。
So then we'll start with a new series very, very soon.
然后我们很快就会开始一个新的系列。
And I don't know if you have any questions or any suggestions about a series, you can
如果你对某个系列有任何问题或建议，你可以
always contact us.
随时联系我们。
Yeah, please do let us know what are the things that you have a hard time with when you're
是的，请告诉我们你在学习英语时遇到哪些困难？
studying English?
有没有让你困惑或觉得难的地方？
Are there things that are confusing or difficult?
我们很乐意听取你的建议，并希望能帮上忙。
We're happy to hear your suggestions and we hope that we can help out.
不过今天我们就到这里。
That's about it for us today, though.
所以下次再见，拜拜。
So until next time, bye.
拜拜。
Bye Bye